<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/</id><title>Zaw Zaw</title><subtitle>ZAW's Personal Blog &amp; Website</subtitle> <updated>2025-06-08T09:06:15+00:00</updated> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> <uri>https://zawzaw.blog/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://zawzaw.blog/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="https://zawzaw.blog/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2025 Zaw Zaw </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Containers from Scratch: Deep Dive into Multi-Host Container Networking (Part II)</title><link href="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-multi-host-container-net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Containers from Scratch: Deep Dive into Multi-Host Container Networking (Part II)" /><published>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-multi-host-container-net/</id> <content src="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-multi-host-container-net/" /> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> </author> <category term="Containerization" /> <summary> This article is Part II of the previously published article, Containers from Scratch: Deep Dive into Single-Host Container Networking. In Part I, you’ve learned how two containers communicate on the same single host, also known as Single-host container networking. In this article, Part II, you’ll learn how Containers (Container A and Container B) running on two different hosts (VMs) communicat... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Containers from Scratch: Deep Dive into Single-Host Container Networking</title><link href="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-single-host-container-net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Containers from Scratch: Deep Dive into Single-Host Container Networking" /><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-single-host-container-net/</id> <content src="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/deep-dive-single-host-container-net/" /> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> </author> <category term="Containerization" /> <summary> This article focused on a deep dive into Container networking; how to run Containers and configure Container Networking from scratch using the tools, such as Linux Namespaces, chroot, unshare and ip. This article also provides a hands-on practical guide on how to run and configure from scratch using these tools. You’ll mainly learn how Container Networking works at the underlying layer (or low ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>A Hands-on Practical Guide to K8s Persistent Storage</title><link href="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/guide-k8s-persistent-storage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Hands-on Practical Guide to K8s Persistent Storage" /><published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-06-01T03:17:40+00:00</updated> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/posts/guide-k8s-persistent-storage/</id> <content src="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/guide-k8s-persistent-storage/" /> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> In Kubernetes, we typically need to create and use Persistent Volumes for stateful applications such as database servers, cache store servers, and so on. In this article, I will share how storage provisioning on Kubernetes works and how to deploy Persistent Volumes dynamically using storage provisioners on the Kubernetes cluster. In this article. I will mainly focus on configuring the Local-Pa... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Configuring RBAC Role Bindings for a User on Kubernetes</title><link href="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/configure-k8s-auth-rbac/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring RBAC Role Bindings for a User on Kubernetes" /><published>2024-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2025-06-01T03:17:40+00:00</updated> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/posts/configure-k8s-auth-rbac/</id> <content src="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/configure-k8s-auth-rbac/" /> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> This article focuses on how to create a user and configure cluster roles and role bindings for that user using Kubernetes built-in RBAC authorization features. Basically, in Kubernetes, we can use the service account as a user, but it is like a non-human user. Generally, every Kubernetes cluster has the default admin kubeconfig file. We usually use this admin kubeconfig file to log in to, acce... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Exploring the Philippines: My Travel Experience to Iloilo City</title><link href="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/explore-the-philippines/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring the Philippines: My Travel Experience to Iloilo City" /><published>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2024-11-25T07:17:04+00:00</updated> <id>https://zawzaw.blog/posts/explore-the-philippines/</id> <content src="https://zawzaw.blog/posts/explore-the-philippines/" /> <author> <name>Zaw Zaw</name> </author> <category term="Travel" /> <summary> In this blog post, I will share all about the Philippines, fascinating facts about the country, visa information, Filipino culture and general knowledge, official currency, official spoken languages, public transportation, and photographs of the famous places in Iloilo City based on my experience. I’ve decided to go to Iloilo City because I think it’s one of the most affordable cities in the Ph... </summary> </entry> </feed>
